arnab-dey-resume.md 2024-11-13

# **Arnab Dey**

Location: Gothenburg, Sweden

Mob: (+46) 0764516092

Mail: arnabdey009@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile

GitHub

#### Summary

 An accomplished professional with more than 14 years of proven experience as a DevOps/CloudOps/Systems Engineer in the Information Technology industry.

- Provided solutions for various business applications on public and hybrid Cloud platforms, using
   CI/CD pipelines, orchestration, infrastructure automation, and Agile tools.
- Managed large and complex development, staging, and production environments, with a strong focus on quality and automation.
- As a senior team member, mentored and supported many colleagues across different projects and domains.
- Well-versed in the SAFe framework and the roles and responsibilities of a Product Owner.

## Skills/Technologies that I work/worked with:

Linux, Shell Scripting (bash), Azure DevOps, Azure Cloud, Jenkins, Gitlab, GitHub, ELK stack, Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Ansible, Python(Scripting), Database management (Mysql/MongoDB), Jira, Miro.

### Experience

Cloud Engineer - 'Stena Metall AB': August 2024 - Present

- Prioritizing and performing tasks from Azure DevOps Kanban board.
- Handpicked and populated tasks in the 'backlog' by reviewing all Microsoft recommendations in order to make sure that we don't miss any technical vulnerabilities, security threats or unnecessary costs.
- Performing tasks mostly based on Azure Governance using Terraform (with Azure Pipelines) and/or Azure portal.
- Also resolving incident and SRs as per SLA from the "Cloud Office" dashbaord in ivanti.

Senior Software Engineer (DevOps) - 'Capgemini Sverige AB': Sep 2021 → July 2024

• Creating and prioritizing backlog in **Azure DevOps** that aligns with the product vision and delivers value to sponsors and users.

arnab-dey-resume.md 2024-11-13

• Upgraded On-prem hardware cluster to **Kubernetes cluster** using xCAT and **Rancher Server and** Rancher Kubernetes Engine(RKE).

- Worked on MLOps platform (developed on an in-house architecture) to figure out solutions for the Al Agile Release Train.
- Created development environment and feature for scalable computing of Azure Databricks clusters using **IaC (Terraform) and GitOps**.
- Defining and managing the product vision and strategy, based on stakeholder/sponsors' needs.
- Collaborating closely with the scrum teams and the scrum master to plan and execute sprints, review the work done, and provide feedback and guidance.
- Communicating with the sponsors regularly to gather feedback, validate assumptions, and demonstrate the product increment.

Senior Business Consultant (DevOps) - 'Tech Mahindra': Feb 2017 → Sep 2021

- Performing a wide range of activities such as providing solutions and implementing CI/CD pipeline for business applications hosted on public/Hybrid cloud platform, orchestrating Microservices using Docker, Kubernetes(Rancher and Bare Metal) and also by implementing GitFlow.
- Working with Azure DevOps, Jenkins, Gitlab(as per requirements) and performing Continuous Integration/Continuous Development.
- Responsible for Log search, indexing and management using tools like Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana.
- Automating the regular activities writing Shell (bash) scripts, automating infrastructure provision through Terraform for hybrid cloud platforms and also resolving the escalated issues.
- Accountable for preparing operational documentations, deployments SOPs and architectural diagrams.

Senior AEM Administrator (Cloud) – 'ICF Next' : Sep 2015 → Jan 2017

- Managed public cloud-based Infrastructure(AWS) which hosted Production/Stage/UAT environments
  of the several clients' web contents by using Ansible/Shell script and also by performing various AEM
  Administration essential tasks as well.
- Implemented Disaster Recovery both at application and infrastructure level.

Unix/Linux Systems Administrator – 'Hewlett Packard Enterprise' : Nov 2011 → Aug 2015

 Managed Unix-based Cloud/on-premise(VMware) platforms in Systems & Storage environment for a leading American Transportation and Logistics. Prepared deployments SOPs and UML-based architectural diagrams occasionally as per demand.

Linux Systems Engineer – 'Axon Networks' : May 2011 → Oct 2011

arnab-dey-resume.md 2024-11-13

• Worked in platform administration in Systems & Storage environment for a leading Indian Online Retail client. Accountable for installation, configuration, upgrade, downgrade, troubleshooting, performance tuning and administration of various Linux based servers.

- Jr. System Administrator 'Bobcares' : Nov 2009 → June 2010
  - Managed Linux VPSs and implemented DNS, DHCP, SMTP servers as per requirement. Performed troubleshooting for RAID/LVM issues.

### Education

B. Tech in Computer Science – West Bengal University of Technology 2005 → 2009